♪The Upper Three hold the seals♪
♪A valiant general, an opera star, and a ruthless cripple♪
♪The Middle Three stir the clouds♪
♪A fiend, a wandering hero, and a master of the blade♪
♪The Lower Three deal in gold♪
♪A beauty, a seer, and a scholar♪
♪The Upper, Middle, and Lower Three♪
♪Represent the nine houses of old Changsha♪
♪Together, they are known♪
♪As the Mystic Nine♪
[Mystic Nine]
[Adapted from the novel of Kennedy Xu]
[Episode 11]
[This story is purely fictional]
Everyone is here.
Where's Xiangu?
Fifth Master!
Master Zhang, he...
Laogou brought Xiangu here.
Let him
deal with it.
Master Zhang,
do you think Xiangu came down here
for another purpose?
Laogou cares about the greater good.
Now that this involves the Japanese forces,
I'm sure he won't prioritize his feelings over the bigger picture.
Our priority now
is this place.
Examine the bodies
and identify the cause of death.
Yes.
[Yoshiyuki Hatoyama Identification Document]
Master,
it's Yoshiyuki Hatoyama.
Yoshiyuki Hatoyama died here.
Master,
everyone here committed seppuku.
Master Zhang!
Look around. Look.
It's not finished yet.
What do you mean?
According to the rules in Fengdu,
a tutelary deity shrine
must contain 72 Star Mansions
in accordance with
its location.
But look.
There are only around 10 Star Mansions here.
And this altar
is incomplete.
No ritual tools
or
offerings.
I think
something must have gone terribly wrong
during construction.
That's why they fled.
But why did the Japanese
come to an unfinished
construction site?
And they
committed seppuku here.
How weird.
Be vigilant. There might be a trap here.
Leave no stones
unturned.
Yes.
Xiangu!
Xiangu.
Laogou.
What are you doing here?
To finish my mission.
Was he already aware that the Japanese
are down here?
Is whatever you're doing
related to them?
Are you doubting me?
Just answer me.
What I'm doing here
has nothing to do with the Japanese.
What were you thinking, then?
Why did you act on your own?
I was so worried.
I promised Ding Qiansui
to explore this place for him.
For that, I marked the places I've been to.
But soon, I realized
my marks appeared in places
I've never been to.
They are even in my handwriting.
[Hurry Up]
So,
I followed the markings here.
Calm down.
Have you forgotten
that this tower almost killed you?
What you saw was an illusion
trying to mislead you.
Remember
the hypothesis you told me?
You said this tower
would take away what we cared about the most.
All of you ran into trouble.
Zhang Qishan's men vanished.
Your dogs,
men,
and even I died before your eyes.
But I
have not encountered anything yet.
I was wondering
if perhaps there was nothing
I truly cared about.
But no, I realized
that the tower has played its trick on me.
It took away something I care a lot about.
What is it?
I'll retrieve it for you.
No one can retrieve what it took away.
It took away my faith.
But I haven't figured everything out yet.
I need time.
It's okay.
I'll keep you company,
okay?
Laogou.
Certain things
require me to find the answers alone.
Master Zhang is waiting for you out there.
If this is your decision,
I'll respect it.
But promise me
that whatever you find,
you must tell me.
Okay?
Okay.
I can tell no one
but you anyway.
Okay.
Blow the whistle if anything.
I'll be there.
Don't worry.
I'll be fine.
Master Zhang.
Fifth Master is back.
Fifth Master, you're back.
Where's Xiangu?
I see it now.
Did you two...
Are you done?
Did you find anything interesting?
I already figured out
why Yoshiyuki Hatoyama came here.
After the copper meteor event,
Yoshiyuki Hatoyama wrote his report.
Inside,
he found a peculiar mural.
The mural
mentioned the Yin Changsheng Mausoleum.
[Letter, Beiping Japanese Chamber of Commerce]
Through the Japanese Chamber of Commerce,
Hatoyama solicited help from Xinyue Restaurant
to inspect the mural.
He was told that it was drawn by Qingwuzi.
The mural contained the secret
of the Yin Changsheng Palace under Changsha.
And it mentioned
that there was a spell
allowing one to travel back
in time.
However, it was difficult to find the entrance,
and it warned others
not to find it.
[Hatoyama Report]
As Qingwuzi's records
regarding the copper meteor proved to be accurate,
Yoshiyuki Hatoyama
firmly believed in Qingwuzi's mural
and the secret of Yin Changsheng.
He was especially fascinated
by the spell that could turn back time.
Therefore,
[Changsha]
he enacted
Operation Changsha.
[Operation Changsha, Secret]
That's odd.
Master Zhang,
we found Operation Catch All
[Top Secret]
on the Japanese
bodies.
How come it becomes
Operation Changsha now?
Both operations
must be connected somehow.
[Hatoyama Report, Addendum]
Hatoyama
submitted the addendum of the Hatoyama Report
and labelled it as top secret.
Then,
he launched Operation Copper Meteor
while devising
Operation Changsha.
[Hatoyama Report]
[Top Secret]
Spicy?
More, please.
[Operation Copper Meteor]
Hatoyama delegated
[Cox Hendry]
Operation Copper Meteor to Cox Hendry
[Operation Copper Meteor]
while he
initiated Operation Changsha.
He
began his work in Changsha.
Later,
I busted Operation Copper Meteor.
We began eliminating Japanese spies in Changsha.
Japanese activity became restricted,
and the spies
were all killed by the Mystic Nine.
[Xiangchun Gate]
But Hatoyama has entered the tower.
He lived in the Otherworld Tower.
But he
was stuck here until now.
Two years ago,
Hatoyama contacted Japan
one last time.
According to his report,
they have already found what they came to find,
but something terrible happened.
Since then,
there have been no more updates from Hatoyama
and his three elite squads.
Tell them
we found
the place.
But
we might no longer be able to get out.
[Household Register, Yoshiyuki Hatoyama, Missing]
Master Zhang,
Yoshiyuki Hatoyama
must have failed
to find the spell to turn back time.
He couldn't find a way to leave,
so he committed seppuku here.
He was a valuable scientist.
There is no way the Japanese government would give up on him.
I think they are still in Changsha.
They even found the one who gave him supplies.
The one who gave him supplies?
Who could do that?
The Mystic Nine cleared all Japanese spies.
So only the Chinese
who stay in Changsha can do this.
For example,
an influential Japanese sympathizer.
Anything else?
The information is in piecemeal fashion.
Most of the pages we read
in the journals
have been torn off.
Like the soldiers above,
they destroyed the information
on them before they died.
They only kept
what they allowed others to see.
There must be something here
that they did not want anyone to find out.
That's a given.
It must be the ultimate truth.
But didn't you say just now
that they committed seppuku because they failed
to find anything useful?
There is more
than meets the eye.
Xiaojin.
Go through the journals again,
especially
the entry before the torn pages.
Spell.
Master.
There are many references to spells
and ponds.
Ponds?
There are many ponds inside.
Did the Japanese mean the ponds inside?
But I've checked inside.
It has nothing except for caves.
Come.
Let's go inside again.
The one in this photo
looks like the Otherworld Patriarch.
Look.
[Precise Divination]
The Otherworld Patriarch?
But it's different from the one you saw
in Liunian Hall.
Come.
Translate it now.
The Japanese said
that after they entered the Otherworld Tower,
they found a statue with hair
at the corner by the main passage.
The statue was 1.7m tall,
and looked like a real person.
Its hair was dark, smooth,
and glossy.
It was estimated
that the hair belonged to a woman
of 18 to 25 years old.
The hair was well-preserved and not wilted.
It was believed
that the statue with hair
was made with unique ritual craftsmanship.
And eerily,
when they touched it,
the statue crumbled into dust.
Only a bundle of hair remained.
They kept it so that they could study it
when they returned.
In that case,
this is not
the Otherworld Patriarch we saw
in Liunian Hall.
Anyway, Eighth Master,
the Japanese probably
placed it here
as a red herring
to mislead us.
Right.
The water and air
are stagnant here.
By right, it is a dead end.
Where is Xiangu?
She's exploring inside.
Master Zhang,
I brought Xiangu here.
No matter what she does,
I hope you won't make it difficult for her.
I'll bear full responsibility.
I'll question her
once we're out.
This is
a natural pond.
The Japanese must have come here as well.
But after they got out,
they committed seppuku.
What exactly happened here?
We came here by using a spell.
So did the Japanese.
According to the mural,
there are two other spells.
Master Zhang,
I've been hiding something from you.
After we split,
the tower made me perform two spells.
I have already performed
all three spells on the mural.
After I performed the second spell,
I noticed that something was off.
But I had to save lives,
so I paid it no mind.
Besides, I also wanted to find out
what would happen after I performed all three spells.
So I played along.
I see it now.
I pretended to be controlled by the tower.
When I tried to kill you previously,
it was all an act for this tower.
I want to deceive this creature.
No.
A creature
would never come up with a scheme like this.
You're right, Master Zhang.
Only the Japanese
could come up with it.
It has always struck me as odd.
After I came down,
I never
found anything about the Japanese.
But suddenly,
everything about the Japanese
suddenly appeared
before us.
Knowing them,
they could've
burned all the evidence here.
Yet they kept the journals.
And the journals
mentioned the ponds many times.
However,
I do not see any traces of the Japanese here.
They erased all traces here on purpose.
And that's their real plan.
They wanted to lure us here.
[The Hope of Victory]
What does this mean?
The hope of victory.
The hope of victory?
[The Hope of Victory]
Time is turning back.
Yoshiyuki Hatoyama!
Fire!
No more bullets?
Stay vigilant.
See if they are dead or alive.
Master Zhang.
Yoshiyuki Hatoyama.
Thank you so much.
The same?
This is Resurrection.
Coming back alive?
You have no idea the miracles
this place holds.
It's a spell, right?
You can call it a spell.
Or you can call it
the ancient Chinese wisdom.
This tower is a priceless jewel
left by your ancestors.
It's a shame. The Chinese now
don't deserve it.
So, everything here
is set up by you.
At first,
we thought
we had you under control.
So, we launched the second phase of our plan.
To our surprise,
you were just acting.
That's okay.
This is enough for us.
What you know is just the tip of the iceberg
of the secret of Yin Changsheng and the Otherworld Patriarch!
Their power is science!
But you're too foolish
to understand.
I'm different.
I spent three years studying this place.
I have mastered the secret of the otherworld.
The operation begins now.
Good.
Operation Catch All
will conclude soon.
Operation Catch All.
Operation Catch Dog.
Your target
is me.
Laogou!
Master Zhang.
Take Xiangu with you.
Thank you, everyone.
Laogou.
Laogou!
Where are the Japanese bodies?
This place is creepy.
Stay vigilant.
It's Yoshiyuki Hatoyama.
He wants to seal this place with bombs
and bury us alive.
Master Zhang.
I don't see anyone inside.
Where did the Japanese
take Laogou to?
This place will collapse soon.
Let's get out first.
I know an exit.
Come with me.
Master Zhang.
Where's Fifth Master?
The Japanese took him away.
Let's run.
This place will collapse soon.
What are you doing?
Fifth Master is inside.
- I have to save him.
- We can only find him
if we're alive. Come.
- Master is still inside! - Come.
- Stop it. - Master!
Master is still inside.
- Run. - Master Zhang!
Quick.
Juanlian.
Where is Master?
Master Zhang.
Fifth Master is missing.
What should we do now?
Fifth Master has been kidnapped by the Japanese.
It seems like their goal of luring us down
is to capture Fifth Master.
They set up everything
for him.
Master is missing.
So we...
The Japanese went out of their way to capture him.
That means he is useful to them.
He will be safe for now.
Let's turn back.
I'll find a way to find him.
Guys!
Gather all our clan's informants in Changsha City.
We'll turn the whole city upside down to find Master if we must.
Yes!
Tell the Patrol Camp
to let the Wus through if they see them
searching with their dogs.
Yes!
Put up a wanted notice for Yoshiyuki Hatoyama.
Then, put up another notice
to collect
any information regarding the Otherworld Patriarch.
Yes!
The event in the Otherworld Tower
shook the Mystic Nine.
Fifth Master is still missing.
The true goal of the Japanese continues to puzzle everyone.
Master Zhang knows Yoshiyuki Hatoyama's plan
is still ongoing.
The key
lies in Wu Laogou.
Unbeknownst to Zhang Qishan,
after everyone left the Otherworld Tower,
[Peace and Serenity]
they all
have a secret.
[Huo's Residence]
Everyone, listen to me now.
We will find Wu Laogou immediately.
[Shushen Hall]
Depart now!
Quick!
I see it now.
[Huo Yuqin]
[Huo Yuyao]
You're saying
that I'm only a leader in name,
not in substance.
Work for Ding Qiansui yourself then.
I understand that you're eager to save Wu Laogou.
But our clan has another priority,
and that is to please Ding Qiansui.
That way, the people you care about
will be safe.
You're using me.
Using you?
Nian,
if you were in my position,
you would have done
the same thing.
Have you done
what Ding Qiansui asked you to do?
Don't tell me
you returned empty-handed?
You're the most skillful member
of our clan.
Surely, you got it?
Ding Qiansui is colluding with the Japanese.
The jar is the key to the spell.
It will bring danger to your life.
Missing person?
Isn't that Fifth Master?
How come he went missing?
That's impossible.
Several days ago, I heard that he was working
with Master Zhang.
Who is that?
If you see the man on this poster,
contact us right away.
Those who come forward with useful information
will be rewarded 1,000 silver coins.
1,000?
1,000.
If you hide information, you'll be deemed as an accomplice
and will be punished equally.
This is...
What does the disappearance of Fifth Master
have anything to do with this Japanese?
[Missing Person]
How would I know?
Master,
the order has been issued.
All 36 checkpoints in the city have been set up
to search for Fifth Master.
We will search every corner.
We have also put up the bounty
to mobilize all citizens
to collect information about Yoshiyuki Hatoyama
and the Otherworld Patriarch.
The Otherworld Patriarch
expended a lot back then
to build a tower underneath Changsha.
He must have left some traces behind.
As for Hatoyama,
he must have come up with a thorough plan
before he lured us down there.
A sly fox has many hideouts.
Capturing him
won't be easy.
What should we do now then?
No one knows the underground of Changsha
better than the Mystic Nine does.
Have you
notified all of them?
Yes.
Is Second Master back?
He is in Changsha as we speak.
But...
Ninth Master is still being imprisoned by Huo Wenhai.
He probably can't escape.
If he can't escape,
we'll just have to break in.
Gather the Mystic Nine.
We'll have a meeting at Xie Residence an hour later.
Yes.
[Xie's Residence]
[Confession Letter]
Xie Jiu,
you have no idea
how much I did to cover you.
Colluding with the Japanese is a serious crime.
If I hadn't suppressed the news,
the Ministry of War
would have dug out many ugly things.
Can't you see what I'm doing for you here?
Sign it.
If you can tell me who you helped,
I'll talk to them
so you and your clan will be safe.
I'm a man of my own word.
Xie Jiu.
Listen.
Playing deaf will not make the whole thing go away.
You're pretty much convicted of sedition right now.
Sign it
and you might still have a clan.
If you don't sign it,
I'll make sure you're there to watch your clan fall apart.
Who says you can come in? Bugger off!
Officer Huo, did you wake up on the wrong side of the bed?
You're grumpy.
What are you doing here?
We're having a meeting.
Leave.
Fellow masters,
Xie Residence has been appropriated by the military
for official business.
I ask for your sincere cooperation, instead of
making this tough for me.
Did the Huo Clan change their rules or something?
It's run by a man now?
Officer Huo, pardon us.
You must be here to attend the meeting on behalf of the Huo Clan.
But the ancestral rule in the Huo Clan dictates
that only women can run the clan.
Have you...
Insolence!
Xie Jiu colludes with the Japanese.
The military is investigating it.
You're trespassing.
Is this a rebellion?
Guards, arrest them!
Guards!
So much talking.
How noisy.
Aren't we here for a meeting?
Where's Zhang Qishan?
Master Zhang.
Everyone, please take a seat.
♪The past fades like smoke♪
♪A choice is made in silence♪
♪In this labyrinthine puzzle♪
♪Who can reach the shore?♪
♪Just an ordinary farewell♪
♪The sun seems to shine bright over our heads♪
♪But this could be our last trip together♪
♪The spring breeze continues outside♪
♪Who was it who left in such haste?♪
♪Caught in the game, the raging waves fall silent♪
♪Who believes in fate?♪
♪For my home and my country, the years pass like a dream♪
♪When the song ends, who will still be waiting?♪
♪With a nod, we bid farewell and set out again♪
♪Take care♪
♪We once raced♪
♪For the dawn♪
♪Ever-lasting bond, a satisfying vindication♪
♪In the web of fate♪
♪No one can escape♪
♪Life and death cut like a blade♪
♪We too were young once♪
♪Fortunate to brave the raging waves together♪
♪Keep the ember lit♪
♪To illuminate the journey ahead♪
♪The spring breeze continues outside♪
♪Who was it who left in such haste?♪
♪Caught in the game, the raging waves fall silent♪
♪Who believes in fate?♪
♪For my home and my country, the years pass like a dream♪
♪When the song ends, who will still be waiting?♪
♪With a nod, we bid farewell and set out again♪
♪Please, do take care of yourself♪